Guide to the Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership Records, 2000-2012 UA.15.03.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership records
2000-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of Durham and Regional Affairs. Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership
Duke University. Facilities Management Department
UA.15.03.0001
4.5 Linear Feet
The Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership(DDNP) collaborates with the twelve communities surrounding the Duke Campus on a wide range of neighborhood support and revitalization projects.The Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership Records contains planning documents, correspondence, meeting notes and other materials on the programs and initiatives sponsored by the Duke Durham Neighborhood Partnership between 2000 and 2012. It also includes materials pertaining to the administrative management of civic affairs and community outreach efforts at Duke University.
Provenance
Duke University Office of Durham and Regional Affairs Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership Transfer, February 2014
Historical Note
The Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership is a division of the Office of Durham & Regional Affairs dedicated to working with the twelve Durham neighborhoods surrounding the Duke Campus. The program was established in the mid-1990’s under the leadership of Duke President Nannerl Keohane after an extensive review of similar community relations projects undertaken at similar colleges and universities. The Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership works with residents within surrounding communities on projects including education, youth outreach, affordable housing and health care. DDNP also seeks to increase ties between Duke University students and Durham through programs such as the Duke-Durham Engage Program.
Collection Overview
The Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership Records contain detailed information on the programs and initiatives sponsored by the Duke Durham Neighborhood Partnership between 2000 and 2012. The collection contains planning documents, correspondence, notes and other materials related to both individual projects, as well as long-term programs such as the John Hope Franklin Youth Scholars program and collaborations with Durham Public Schools and Walltown Neighborhood Ministries. The collection also includes administrative materials employed by Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership committees and staff members including meeting minutes, background research, program evaluations and staff correspondence.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Community development, Urban -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University. Office of Durham and Regional Affairs. Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership; Duke University. Office of Durham and Regional Affairs. Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership; Duke University. Facilities Management Department
- Programs and Initiatives Series, 1
  Scope and Contents
  The Programs and Initiatives series contains materials relating to the different projects implemented by the Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership (DDNP). Materials been organized into subseries around major areas of interest such as Durham Public Schools, the Facilities Management Department at Duke University, the John Hope Franklin Youth Scholars program and the Walltown community, as well as a General Projects subseries.
  - Durham Public Schools, 1
    The Durham Public Schools subseries contains correspondence, planning materials, presentations and other notes pertaining to collaborations between the DDNP and Durham Public Schools, including projects at E.K. Powe Elementary School and Watts Montessori School.
    - E.K. Powe (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - E.K. Powe: Home Depot, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - E.K. Powe: Science Lab, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Internal Parters (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Spanish Langauge Leap (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Watts, 2001-2013 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Watts: Montessori Transitions (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Facilities Management Department, 2
    The Facilities Management Department subseries focuses on projects in which the Facilities Management Department contributed time and expertise to collaborate with the DDNP and local communities on a variety of projects.
    - Facilities Management Department (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Duke Facilities Mgmt. and the NPI 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Duke Facilities Mgmt. and the NPI 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - FMD, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - FMD Wish Lists, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - FMD/NP Projects, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Work Zone: FMD (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - John Hope Franklin Scholars, 3
    The John Hope Franklin Scholars subseries encompasses materials relating to the John Hope Franklin Young Scholars program, a program focused on exploring topics in African-American history with young Durham students. This subseries contains materials related to participant recruitment, curriculum and field trip planning, as well as correspondence among the board of advisors.
    - Flyer and Application Material, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - JHF Evaluation, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wilmington Trip, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - JHF, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - JHF 11/10 Program, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - JHF Focus Group Notes, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - JHF Evaluation (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - JHF Charleston Trip (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General Projects, 4
    The General Projects subseries is comprised of correspondence, news articles, planning materials and other notes about Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership projects including the Duke School Days Program, the Duke-Durham Engage Program and the renovation of the old Duke Laundry into senior housing units.
    - 9/11 Day of Service, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Blitz Build, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bull City Forward (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Council for Collaborative Action (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Crest Street History (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Crest Street Neighborhood Clean-up (Photos) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Crest Street Holiday Gathering, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Dive into Durham, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Duke University Neighborhood Partnership Initiative (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Duke Engage-Durham, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Duke Engage-Durham, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Duke Engage-Durham, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Duke Engage-Durham, Summer 2011 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Duke Engage-Durham, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Duke, Durham and Beyond, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Duke Laundry Project (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Gattis Street Project (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Geo-Plunge/Game Day (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Grabarak (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Kaboom! Project (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Leadership Triangle: College Edition, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Leadership Triangle: College Edition, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Leadership in a Changing World: Nominations, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Legacy Partners MOAs (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Make a Difference Day, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - MLK Planning Committee, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Million Meals, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Million Meals, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Neighborhoods (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Northside Baptist Church (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - NPI Tech Center Project (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Operation Snowball (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Outdoor Learning Environment (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Physics for Girls (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - St. James Baptist Church (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - St. James/Carter Plaques (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - School Days, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - School Days, 2008-2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - School Days, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - SWCD 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - SWCD 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Student Engagement, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Student Engagement, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Student Groups, 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Trinity Park-Duke Students (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Trinity Park Action Committee, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Walltown Children's Theatre: Joseph Henderson (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Walltown Children's Theatre: Bangin' (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - West End Community Center (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Gateways Project (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Healthcare Issues in SW Central Durham (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - HOPE Project (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Walltown Children's Theatre (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Watts Hospital/Hilldale Neighborhood Association (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - MISC (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Walltown
    The Walltown subseries contains materials related to projects undertaken in the neighboring community of Walltown, including many collaborations with Walltown Neighborhood Ministries. This subseries also includes information on DDNP projects to help build affordable housing units, support the Walltown Health Clinic and efforts to implement the Walltown Connectivity Project to improve internet access for residents of the neighborhood.
    - Walltown (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Walltown, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Walltown Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Walltown Neighborhood History Project (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Walltown Research (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Atlantic Foundation Proposal (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Walltown Support Summary (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Walltown Health Clinic (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Walltown Home Ownership Project Self-Help (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Walltown News (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Walltown School (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Knox St. Grocery (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Walltown (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Walltown Misc. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 1 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 2 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 3 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 4 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Mnistries 5, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 7 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 6, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries 8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - WNM, June 15, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministees: 501-C3 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Walltown Ministries: Knox Street Project (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries: Letter to Self-Help in sublease, Healing of the Heart Ministry, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Walltown Neighborhood Ministries: Letter to Self-Help in sublease, Healing of the Heart Ministry, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - WNM: Offer to Purhase Contract 1227 Berkeley St., 2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walltown Connectivity Project: Digital Connectors (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Walltown Connectivity Project: One Economy (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Walltown Connectivity Project:CISCO, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Administrative Material Series, 2
  The Administrative Materials series compiles materials related to the administrative management of the Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership. Materials have been organized in subseries by their administrative function such as Community/Civic Engagement, the DDNP Advisory Board and Evaluation materials, as well as a General Materials subseries.
  - Civic/Community Engagement
    The Community/Civic Engagement subseries includes notes and correspondence relating to the Center for Civic Engagement and Department of Community Affairs, including planning documents, notes from annual meetings and correspondence among board members.
    - Council on Civic Engagement: DDNP, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Council on Civic Engagement, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Community Affairs Planning (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Center for Civic Engagement (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Carnegie Classification: Community Engagement (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Civic Engagement, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Public Affairs Retreat, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Public Affairs Retreat, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Community Affairs: Internal (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Office of Community Affairs (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - DDNP Advisory Board
    The DDNP Advisory Board subseries contains meeting minutes, correspondence, reports and other materials used during meetings of the Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership Advisory Board.
    - Meeting Minutes, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Meeting Minutes, April, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Meeting Minutes, October, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Meeting Minutes, April, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Meeting Minutes, April, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Meeting Minutes, October, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Meeting Minutes, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Meeting Minutes, November, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Conference Call, January, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Meeting Minutes, Jun-Oct, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Meeting Minutes, October, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Meeting Minutes, January, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Meeting Minutes, August, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Meeting Minutes, October, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Meeting Minutes, March, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Meeting Minutes, September, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Meeting Minutes, February, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Evaluations
    The Evaluations subseries includes external and internal reviews of the impact of the Duke-Durham Neighborhood Partnership on surrounding communities and evaluations of individual projects such as the School Days program.
    - Duke School Days: Program Evaluation (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Program/Project Evaluation (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - External Evaluation, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - General Materials
    The General Materials subseries is comprised of correspondence, planning documents and other notes used by staff members of the Duke- Durham Neighborhood Partnership.
    - Board of Ed Presentation (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Community Proposal (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - David Stein Correspondece (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Duke + Neighbors, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Duke's Economic Impact and Community Assesment Planning: West End and SWCD (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Mayor's Talking Points, January, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - NPI Summary, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - NPI Census Information (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - General NPI Materials (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Maps (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Publicity (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Publicity 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Revitalization Plans 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Revitalization Plans 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)